<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Benjamin Sturgeon</title><link>https://benjamin-sturgeon.github.io/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Benjamin Sturgeon</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 20:10:41 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://benjamin-sturgeon.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Artifact Three Narrative</title><link>https://benjamin-sturgeon.github.io/posts/artifact_three_narrative/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 20:10:41 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://benjamin-sturgeon.github.io/posts/artifact_three_narrative/</guid><description>&lt;p>Artifact Three Narrative&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Travlr Authentication System Enhancement and Debugging&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Artifact Overview&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The artifact that I have chosen for this category is my full-stack development website utilizing the MEAN stack. This application is derived from my CS-465 Full-Stack Development 1 class. I have chosen this artifact because it provides me with a great framework to showcase my ability to improve a full-stack application. I specifically planned to implement Authorization security procedures for users which access the Mongo Database in this application.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Code Review</title><link>https://benjamin-sturgeon.github.io/posts/codereview/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 14:31:04 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://benjamin-sturgeon.github.io/posts/codereview/</guid><description>&lt;p>I completed a code review prior to implementing improvements to the projects. The link to this code review is provided here:
&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/ULIRyS-XVs4" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://youtu.be/ULIRyS-XVs4&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is the Script for the code review. It addresses improvmenent for three seperate projects:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Code Review Script&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Category One: Software Design and Engineering&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Provide a clear, complete description of existing code
&lt;strong>functionality&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>What does the code do?&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The first artifact that I will be improving is a Weight
Tracking Application. This simple Java application is
designed to run on Android OS and provides users with a
way to track their weight. They can also set their goal
weight and opt in to receive a text notification once
their goal weight is reached. User accounts are created
during the initial login screen of the application. Data
is kept locally on the device via a MongoDB schema.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Focus on the features and functions of the existing code.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Artifact One Narrative</title><link>https://benjamin-sturgeon.github.io/posts/artifact_one_narrative/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2025 20:10:41 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://benjamin-sturgeon.github.io/posts/artifact_one_narrative/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Artifact One: Weight Tracking Application&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Briefly describe the artifact. What is it? When was it created?&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>The &lt;em>Weight Tracking Application&lt;/em> is a mobile-based Android solution designed to assist users in monitoring their weight progress through interactive features, intuitive design, and goal-driven notifications. Created as part of my coursework in 2025, the initial version implemented basic logging and visualization capabilities. Enhancements brought refined user interface elements, responsive layouts, and meaningful real-time engagement, transforming the app into a more complete, user-centric experience.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Artifact Two Narrative</title><link>https://benjamin-sturgeon.github.io/posts/artifact_two_narrative/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2025 20:10:41 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://benjamin-sturgeon.github.io/posts/artifact_two_narrative/</guid><description>&lt;p>Artifact Two Narrative&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Narrative: Enhancing the AAC Grazioso Salvare Dashboard&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Brief Description of the Artifact&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This artifact is an interactive Jupyter Dash application, built to visualize animal rescue data efficiently using MongoDB queries, Dash components, and Plotly visualizations. Originally created as part of the Southern New Hampshire University CS 499 Capstone, the dashboard provides users with filtering options, an interactive data table, a map visualization, and a pie chart representation of rescued animal breeds.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>